Guide to the Mary Coolidge Rentschler Collection 1793-2000 (bulk, 1875-1950) MS 2999
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. Photographic prints and negatives
  - Subseries II.A. Standard print boxes
    - Standard prints (box 3 of 15) (Offsite-box Pho (std)-3)
      • Rentschler. Architecture: Exterior view of Rentschler office building during flood, Hamilton, Ohio, 1913
      • Rentschler/Atkins. Trip to Media Luna, Cuba, 1921
      • Rentschler. Architecture: Hamilton, Ohio farm, circa 1921–1943
      • Rentschler. Press photograph of Swedish royalty attending wedding of Ailsa Mellon, daughter of Andrew Mellon, to David Este Bruce, circa 1926
      • Rentschler. Gordon S. Rentschler & Mary C. Rentschler trip to Latin America, including Brazil, 1927
      • Rentschler. Hamilton Rentschlers in front of Dayton Street home, circa 1920s
      • Rentschler. Jekyll Island, GA (Go-Kart), circa 1930s
      • Rentschler. Moisie Salmon Fishing Trip, Quebec, Canada, circa 1930s
      • Rentschler. Emma & Minnie Prior preparing the farm hams, 1933 January 13
      • Rentschler. Locust Valley, Long Island home in winter, 1934?
      Rentschler. Function: National Cash Register Company, Dayton, Ohio, 1938–1947
    - Standard prints (box 4 of 15) (Offsite-box Pho (std)-4)
      • Rentschler. Coronation of King Ah-Sar-Ben XLVI Wm. Martin Jeffers (Pres. U.P.R.R.), Queen Gwendolyn Ruth Sacks, Omaha, NB, October 1940
      • Rentschler. Captions to Dayton, Ohio, street scenes, 1940? Photographs are missing
      • Rentschler. Architecture: Locust Valley, Long Island home, 1940s
      • Rentschler. Function: Oberlin College Anniversary, 1940s?
      • Rentschler. Architecture: Replanting garden at Hamilton, Ohio farm, 1941
      • Rentschler. Trip out West, inc. image of Humphrey Bogart, 1941
      • Rentschler. Hamilton, Ohio farm, pre-1942
      • Rentschler. Function: 70th Birthday of Harry Wolfe, Dayton, Ohio, 1942 April 26
      • Rentschler. Function: United Aircraft Corporation dinner, circa 1946–1948?
      • Rentschler. Hamilton, Ohio farm. House of John and Clara Smith, 1947
      • Rentschler. Trip to Matanzas Branch of National City Bank, Havana, Cuba, 1948
      • Rentschler. Hubner house fire on the farm, Hamilton, Ohio, circa 1940s?
      • Rentschler. Function: American Institute of Banking annual banquet. Gordon S. Rentschler receiving honorary membership, 1946 February 2
      • Rentschler. The farm, Hamilton, Ohio, circa 1950
      • Rentschler. Architecture: Exterior views of Hamilton, Ohio house on 105 South "D," 1950s
      • Rentschler. Function: Thanksgiving, New York, 1963
      • Rentschler. Hamilton Farm, Ohio, 1966–1972, inc. Mary H. Schwab's 93rd-95th birthdays
    - Standard prints (box 5 of 15) (Offsite-box Pho (std)-5)
      • Rentschler. Function: Mary C. Rentschler 80th birthday party, New York, 1972 June 15
      • Rentschler. Architecture: Exterior views of Hamilton, Ohio farm, 1976
      • Rentschler. Architecture: Exterior views of Little Farm, Ohio, circa 1970s
      • Rentschler. Architecture: Demolition of buildings at Little Farm, Ohio, 1976
      • Rentschler. Function: Mary C. Rentschler funeral, Hamilton, Ohio, 1988 August 29
      • Rentschler. 20 color prints of the Safe from the S.S. Maine, Hamilton, Ohio Farm, undated
      • Shepley. Boats, Marion, Massachusetts, circa 1901
      • Shepley. Architecture: Exterior view of home of Chief Justice Ether Shepley, Portland, Maine, circa 1920
      • Shepley. Meadow Island Yacht Club, Marion, Massachusetts, 1931
      • Shurtleff, Barnabas. Gravestones
    - Standard prints (box 6 of 15) (Offsite-box Pho (std)-6)
      Allen, Anne Claflin
      Allen, Margaret Shepley
      Amory, John Austin
      Amory, Louise Lionberger
      Atkins, David
      Atkins, Edwin Farnsworth
      Atkins, Edwin Farnsworth Jr.
      Atkins, Edwin Farnsworth III
      Atkins, Robert Wrisley
      Baldwin
      Barrett, Anne Dorothea Nagel
      Beeler, C. S.
      Benedict, Susan Stanton
      Benninghofen, Elsa
      Benzing, Andy
      Brakley, George
      Brant
      Breeden, Faith Atkins Witter
      Brennan, Eugene
      Briggs, Mary Merwin Shepley
      Buckley, George D.
      Bullard, Hilda Greenleaf
      Bunsen, Mrs. Julius
      Burzing, Andy
      Cassady, Ann Rentschler
      Claflin, Helen Atkins
      Coolidge, Albert Sprague
      Coolidge, Alison Jones
      Coolidge, Alison Richardson
      Coolidge, Charles Allerton Sr.
      Coolidge, Charles Allerton Jr.
      Coolidge, Charles Allerton III
      Coolidge, Constance Crowninshield
      Coolidge, David Hill Jr.
    - Standard prints (box 7 of 15) (Offsite-box Pho (std)-7)
      Coolidge, David Hill Sr.
      Coolidge, Elizabeth
      Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague
      Coolidge, Family Group
      Coolidge, Dr. Frederick Shurtleff
      Coolidge, Isabel
      Coolidge, Isabella Shurtleff
      Coolidge, Julia Shepley
      Councilman, Christina Drummond
      Councilman, Elizabeth L.
      Councilman, Family Group Councilman, Isabella Coolidge
      Councilman, Dr. William
      Crowley, Julia Coolidge Deane
      Cullen, Will
      Cunningham, Charles
      Cunningham, Louise Mills
      Cunningham, Thomas Jr.
      Cutler, Donald F.
      Cutler, Donald F. Jr.
      Cutler Family Group
    - Standard prints (box 8 of 15) (Offsite-box Pho (std)-8)
      Cutler, Margaret Lionberger
      Cutler, Philip
      Daire, Sidney W.
      Deane, Family Group
      Deane, Frederick
      Deane, Frederick Jr.
      Deane, Julia Shepley Coolidge
      Deeds, Mrs. Edith
      Deeds, Colonel Edward
      Dorn, Esther
      Dorn, Fred
      Dorn, Mina
      Dorn, Reverend
      Dorn, Mrs.
      Dorsey, Tommy A.
      Elliott, Brant
      Fishback, Elizabeth (Tinnie)
      Ford, Edsel
      Ford, Henry
      Ford, Henry, Mrs.
      Grant, Julianna Sweetser
      Hart, Boies C.
      Hitchcock, Ethan Allen
      Hobart, Janet Elliott
      Hollister, Ellen Rollins
      Hooper, Jack
      Hooper, Margo
      Hughes, Llewellyn Frederick
      Hutchinson, Charles L.
    - Standard prints (box 9 of 15) (Offsite-box Pho (std)-9)
      Kehrn [Kehm?], Charles
      Kehrn [Kehm?], Mrs. Charles
      Kehrn [Kehm?], Family Group
      Kehrn [Kehm?], Henry
      Kehrn [Kehm?], Katherine Schwab
      Kennett, Alfred (sp?)
      Kettering, Charles
      Keyes, Emily Catlin Shepley
      Kolbenstetter, Ray
      Lehrmann(?), Anne Shepley Lionberger
      Leomis, Violet Amory
      Leonard, Bill
      Lionberger, Arthur David
      Lionberger, Family Group
      Lionberger, Isaac Henry
      Lionberger, John Shepley Sr.
      Lionberger, John Shepley Jr.
      Lionberger, Mary Louise Shepley
      Lionberber, Mary Ruth
      Lowrey, Charles Frederick
      Lowrey, Mary Coolidge Rentschler
      Mathews, Susan Anderson Sweetser
      Mayer, Elizabeth Tacy W.
      McGuider, Esther Hosmer?
      McKinney, Dorothy
      Mead, George H. Jr.
      Millikin, Dan
      Morey, Madge
      Morgan, J. P.
      Morrison, Suzanne
      Nagel, Anne Shepley
      Nagel, Charles
    - Standard prints (box 10 of 15) (Offsite-box Pho (std)-10)
      Nagel, Charles Jr.
      Nagel, Family Group
      Patch, Helen Rentschler
      Post, Charles
      Prior, Emma & Minnie
      Putnam, Anne Shepley
      Putnam, Edith Nagel
      Rentschler, Barbara Schlosser
      Rentscher, Charles Mitchell
      Rentschler, Elizabeth Hemann
      Rentschler, Family Group
      Rentschler, Frederica Schlaff
      Rentschler, Frederick Brant
      Rentschler, George Adam Sr.
      Rentschler, George Adam Jr. (Bud)
      Rentschler, George Adam III
    - Standard prints (box 11 of 15) (Offsite-box Pho (std)-11)
      Rentschler, Gordon Sohn, 1890–1929
      Rentschler, Gordon Sohn, 1930–1939
      Rentschler, Gordon Sohn, 1940–1948
      Rentschler, Henry Adam
      Rentschler, Henry and Peter Earl (Family Group)
      Rentschler, Mary Coolidge, 1892–1904
    - Standard prints (box 12 of 15) (Offsite-box Pho (std)-12)
      Rentschler, Mary Coolidge, 1905–1919
      Rentschler, Mary Coolidge, 1920–1949
      Rentschler, Mary Coolidge, 1950–1979
      Rentschler, Mildred Rebekah Parrish
      Rentschler, Peter R.
      Rentschler, Phoebe Schwab
      Rentschler, Rita Mitchell
      Rentschler, Robert Peter
    - Standard prints (box 13 of 15) (Offsite-box Pho (std)-13)
      Rentschler, Suzanne Snowden
      Rentschler, Walter
      Ryerson, Martin A.
      Ryerson, Mrs. Martin A.
      Schwab, Mary Hemann (Aunt Mary)
      Schwab, Peter
      Schwab, Phoebe
      Schwenn, Mary Elizabeth
      Shaw, Abby Shurtleff
      Shaw, Ichabod
      Shaw, Priscilla Atwood
      Shepley (2 unidentified family portraits; maybe a Clapp and John Rutledge Shepley?)
      Shepley, Arthur Behn
      Shepley, Emily Kayser Catlin
      Shepley, Ethan Allen Hitchcock
      Shepley, Family Group (Arthur Behn)
      Shepley, Family Group (George Foster)
    - Standard prints (box 14 of 15) (Offsite-box Pho (std)-14)
      Shepley, Family Group (John Foster)
      Shepley, George Foster Sr.
      Shepley, George Foster Jr.
      Shepley, Hayden Richardson
      Shepley, Henry Richardson Sr.
      Shepley, Henry Richardson Jr.
      Shepley, John Foster
      Shepley, John Rutledge
      Shepley, Julia Hayden
      Shepley, Julia Hayden Richardson
      Shepley, Mary Augusta Clapp
      Shepley, Philip
      Shepley, Robert Gardiner
      Shepley, Sarah Hitchcock
      Shurtleff, Abigail Atwood
      Shurtleff, Benjamin II (copy of photograph of painting)
      Shurtleff, Benjamin III (copy of photograph of painting)
      Shurtleff, Eliza Carleton
      Shurtleff, Sally Shaw
      Sizer, Carolyn Foster
      Skinner, Margaret Clarkson Lionberber
      Smith, Clara and John
      Sohn, Mrs. Henry
      Sprague, A. A.
      Sprague, Mrs. A.
      Stanton, Gordon Rentschler
      Stanton, L. Lee
      Stanton, Louis L. Jr.
    - Standard prints (box 15 of 15) (Offsite-box Pho (std)-15)
      Stanton, Phoebe Rentschler
      Sturgis, R. Clipston
      Sullivan, Bridget
      Sweetser, Family Group
      Sweetser, John Anderson
      Sweetser, Mrs. John A. (who is this?)
      Sweetser, Mary Nagel
      Sweetser, Violet Shepley
      Taylor, Eunice
      Viera, Frank
      Wakefield, Albert
      Waldon, Helen Rentschler
      Waldon, Sidney Dunn
      Wesco, Thomas
      Wigglesworth, Constance
      Wigglesworth, Isabella Councilman
      Witter, David G.
      Witter, Dean III (Kip)
      Witter, Rebekah Ferran
      Witter, Susan Rentschler
      Witter, William D.
      Witter, William Perkins
      Woods, Virginia Ann
      Wright, Orville
  - Subseries II.B. Oversize print boxes
    - Oversize prints (box 1 of 4) (Offsite-box Pho (ovz)-1)
      • Atkins, Edwin Farnsworth, Jr.
      • Coolidge, Charles Allerton, Jr.
      • Coolidge, Charles Allerton, Sr. (including oversize photograph of monument designed by Daniel Chester French circa 1922—photograph taken by / belonging to CAC, Sr.?)
      • Facio, Marcial Humberto Francisco de Paula
      • Lowrey, Mary Coolidge Rentschler
      • Rentschler, Family Group
      • Rentschler, Frederick Brant
      • Rentschler, George Adam, Sr.
      • Rentschler, Gordon Sohn, 1930–1939
      • Rentschler, Gordon Sohn, 1940–1948
      • Rentschler, Gordon Sohn (6 portrait folders, undated)
      • Rentschler, Gordon Sohn (misc. panoramic images of official functions)
      • Rentschler, Gordon Sohn (caricature; drawing)
      • Rentschler, Mary Coolidge 1916 (wedding to E. F. Atkins)
      • Rentschler, Mary Coolidge
      • Rentschler, Phoebe Schwab
      • Schwab, Mary Hemann (Aunt Mary)
      • Schwab, Peter
    - Oversize prints (box 2 of 4) (Offsite-box Pho (ovz)-2)
      • Waldon, Helen Dorothy Rentschler (3 folders, including Steichen prints)
      • Waldon, Sidney Dunn (6 folders, inc. Sequoia? Road trip print)
    - Oversize prints (box 3 of 4) (Offsite-box Pho (ovz)-3)
      • Waldon, Sidney Dunn (Sequoia and Sage Brush road trip, 1919, taken by SDW. Folder includes photocopies of correspondence from SDW to Gordon S. Rentschler, Colonel E. A. Deeds, and Edie Odell. Also "Desert Rats First Annual Assembly 1920" leather-bound document.)
      • Waldon, Sidney Dunn (Miscellaneous landscape photographs taken by SDW. Also 1 photograph of SDW [in Egypt?].)
      • Hamilton, Ohio Farm (undated)
      Misc. newspaper clippings (inc. images of Mrs. G. A. Rentschler, Mrs. Sohngen, and the Hamilton, Ohio flood, 1913.)
    - Oversize prints (box 4 of 4) [cylinder] (Offsite-box Pho (ovz)-4)
      • Aerial photograph of Hamilton farm, Ohio.
  - Subseries II.C. Albums / framed photographs
    - Coolidge, Family group. Coolidge family album, circa 1890s (Offsite-box 9, Box Pho (Alb)-1)
    - Renstchler, Mary Coolidge. House at Marion, MA (inc. construction), 1893-1931 (Offsite-box 9, Box Pho (Alb)-2)
    - Rentschler, Mary Coolidge, 1904-1918 (Offsite-box 9, Box Pho (Alb)-3)
    - Shepley, Mary A. C. & Shepley, John R., circa 1870s?, undated (Offsite-box 9, Box Pho (Alb)-4)
    - Waldon, Sidney Dunn. Sequoia and Sage Brush road trip (album 1 of 5), 1919 (Offsite-box 10, Box Pho (Alb)-5)
    - Waldon, Sidney Dunn. Sequoia and Sage Brush road trip (album 2 of 5), 1919 (Offsite-box 10, Box Pho (Alb)-6)
    - Waldon, Sidney Dunn. Sequoia and Sage Brush road trip (album 3 of 5), 1919 (Offsite-box 11, Box Pho (Alb)-7)
    - Waldon, Sidney Dunn. Sequoia and Sage Brush road trip (album 4 of 5), 1919 (Offsite-box 11, Box Pho (Alb)-8)
    - Waldon, Sidney Dunn. Sequoia and Sage Brush road trip (album 5 of 5), 1919 (Offsite-box 12, Box Pho (Alb)-9)
    - Waldon, Sidney Dunn. Africa road trip (volume 1 of 4), 1924-1925 (Offsite-box Pho (Alb)-10A)
    - Waldon, Sidney Dunn. Africa road trip (volume 2 of 4), 1924-1925 (Offsite-box Pho (Alb)-10B)
    - Waldon, Sidney Dunn. Africa road trip (volume 3 of 4), 1924-1925 (Offsite-box Pho (Alb)-10C)
    - Waldon, Sidney Dunn. Africa road trip (volume 4 of 4), 1924-1925 (Offsite-box Pho (Alb)-10D)
    - Young, Caroline & Schwab, Phoebe? Ambrotype / tintype?, circa 1860? (Offsite-box 9, Box Pho (Alb)-11)
    - Rentschler, Gordon S. Photograph album of friends; also certificates, 1930s-1940s (Offsite-box 12, Box Pho (Alb)-12)
  - Subseries II.D. Negatives
    - Coolidge, Charles A., Sr. Leland Stanford negatives of the construction of Stanford University, California, 1887 (Offsite-box Neg-1, Box Pho (neg)-1)
    - Coolidge, Charles A., Sr. Varied, inc. regiments, boat trips (smaller of 2 boxes), 1918-1919 (Offsite-box Neg-1, Box Pho (neg)-2)
    - Coolidge, Charles A., Sr. Varied, inc. regiments, boat trips. Includes original album and index. (larger of 2 boxes), 1918-1919 (Offsite-box Neg-1, Box Pho (neg)-3)
    - Waldon, Sidney D. Sage Brush and Sequoia road trip, 1919 (Offsite-box Neg-2, Box Pho (neg)-4)
    - Waldon, Sidney D. Pack trip (out West), 1919 (Offsite-box Neg-2, Box Pho (neg)-5)
    - Waldon, Sidney D. Trip to Europe, 1928 (Offsite-box Neg-3, Box Pho (neg)-6)
    - Waldon, Sidney D. Photopositives & negatives inc. Pine Knob, MI; Marion, MA; Locust Valley, NY, 1928-1940 (Offsite-box Neg-3, Box Pho (neg)-7)
    - Waldon, Sidney D. Pine Knob, MI; Locust Valley, NY, 1929-1940 (Offsite-box Neg-4, Box Pho (neg)-8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1920s-1988 (Offsite-box Neg-4, Box Pho (neg)-9)
      Nitrate, glass plate negative, kodachrome color slides (Mary C. Rentschler funeral, 1988).
- Series III. Mary Rentschler Lowrey addition
  Separated Materials
  Loose material integrated into Series I:
  1) The Daily Princetonian, June 12, 1907
  2) Western Association of Princeton Clubs, Chicago, May 5-6, 1916
  3) Fortune, November 1930
  4) GSR newspaper obituaries, 1948
  5) Surveyor's maps of Butler County, Hamilton, Ohio, 1961
  6) Architectural blueprints for remodeling of GSR farm, 1977
  - Subseries III.A. Print [sic] Collection
    - Real Estate, Hamilton, Ohio, 1968-1978 (Offsite-box MRL-1, Folder 1)
      Hamilton, Ohio Farm: real estate correspondence and deeds (see large cylinder for oversize maps and blueprints).
    - Real Estate, Hamilton, Ohio (continued), 1971-1994 (Offsite-box MRL-1, Folder 2)
      Hamilton, Ohio Farm: real estate correspondence.
    - Real Estate, Hamilton, Ohio (continued), 1978-1982 (Offsite-box MRL-1, Folder 3)
      Hamilton, Ohio Farm: correspondence and photographs for repairs and renovations to farm.
    - Real Estate, Hamilton, Ohio (continued), 1993 June (Offsite-box MRL-1, Folder 4)
      Hamilton, Ohio Farm: newspaper clippings re: sale of farm.
    - Cincinnati Art Museum, 1942-1989 (Offsite-box MRL-1, Folder 5)
      Correspondence and photographs re: restoration of painting of Schwab family members.
    - Cincinnati Art Museum (continued), 1986, 1988, 1992 (Offsite-box MRL-1, Folder 6)
      Artist entries in biographical dictionaries (photocopies). Bulletins from Cincinnati Art Museum.
    - Cincinnati Art Museum (continued), 1991-1993 (Offsite-box MRL-1, Folder 7)
      Correspondence and appraisal of clothing and furniture (inc. photographs) belonging to Helen R. Waldon; Deed of gift for clothing to CAM.
    - Hillforest Historical Foundation, Aurora, N.Y., 1991-1995 (Offsite-box MRL-1, Folder 8)
      Correspondence, photographs, and information packet re: gifts to the Foundation from MRL.
    - Fine Arts Museum of San Francisco, 1995 (Offsite-box MRL-1, Folder 9)
      Correspondence re: gift from MRL.
    - Correspondence re: Republic Motor Car Co.; SDW packing list for Sagebrush and Sequoia road trip, circa 1919-1995 (Offsite-box MRL-1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence re: bequest to GSR from Mr. Gaines, 1922-1997 (Offsite-box MRL-1, Folder 11)
    - Photocopied excerpt from The Book of Gardens and Gardening, 1924 (Offsite-box MRL-1, Folder 12)
      (Locust Valley garden of Paul D. Cravath.)
    - The Season's Greetings (card), SDW and HRW, 1937-1938 (Offsite-box MRL-1, Folder 13)
    - Programs, invites, guest lists, and correspondence re: social occasions involving MRL, 1939-1952 (Offsite-box MRL-2, Folder 1)
    - Record (salaries / accounts?), 1943-1961 (Offsite-box MRL-2, Folder 2)
    - Number 8 - Gordon Sohn Rentschler tribute, 1948 (Offsite-box MRL-2, Folder 3)
    - The Kettering Digest, 1956 August (Offsite-box MRL-2, Folder 4)
    - Time Book for HRW, 1959-1966 (Offsite-box MRL-2, Folder 5)
    - Booklet: Edward A. Deeds, 1874-1960 (Offsite-box MRL-2, Folder 6)
    - Bulletin: Gray & Ductile Iron News, 1975 April 18 (Offsite-box MRL-2, Folder 7)
    - Publication, 1975 (Offsite-box MRL-2, Folder 8)
      Letters and manuscripts in the Pierpont Morgan Library, N.Y., 1975; letter from Doris A. Hamburg to Mary C. Rentschler, 1975 September 30.
  - Subseries III.B. Albums/Framed Photographs
    - Princeton photographic album, 1907 (Offsite-box 13, Box MRL-3)
    - Schwab, Katie / Phoebe? Framed (red velvet), undated (Offsite-box 13, Box MRL-4)
    - Schwab, Katie / Phoebe? Framed (brown velvet), undated (Offsite-box 13, Box MRL-5)
  - Subseries III.C. Photoprint Collection
    - Individuals / Groups, circa 1887-1966 (Box MRL-?)
      • "Brant and Bayley (surnames), cousins of Suzanne Morrison, next-door neighbors in Hamilton, OH" [Eliza Gregory]
      • Coolidge, Charles A. Jr. (½ length portrait), c. 1950s?
      • Gregory, Mary L., Charles F. Lowrey Jr., 1962
      • Lowrey, Charles F. Jr. at John Smith's house, Hamilton, Ohio farm, c. 1960s?
      • Lowrey, Mary R., c. 1929?
      • Lowrey, Mary R., Faith A. Witter, Helen R. Waldon, Phoebe R. Stanton (oversize), c. 1930
      • Lowrey, Mary R., Phoebe R. Stanton, Faith A. Witter, c. 1930
      • Lowrey, Mary R., in a perambulator, c. 1930 (taken by SDW?)
      • Lowrey, Mary R., picking flowers (4 views), Locust Valley, Long Island, 1932 (taken by SDW #400-5-11 to 400-5-14)
      • Lowrey, Mary R., outdoors, holding up a page (of the Herald Tribune), Locust Valley, Long Island, 1932 (taken by SDW #400-5-15)
      • Lowrey, Mary R., and Mary Sweetser outdoors, with pages of the Herald Tribune, Locust Valley, Long Island, 1932 (taken by SDW #400-5-16 to 400-5-20)
      • Lowrey, Mary R., outdoors by the flower bush, Locust Valley, Long Island, 1932 (taken by SDW #400-5-21 to 400-5-24)
      • Lowrey, Mary R., outdoors playing with doll furniture, Locust Valley, Long Island, c. 1933 (taken by SDW #400-6-5)
      • Lowrey, Mary R., outdoors with Phoebe R. Stanton, playing with doll furniture, Locust Valley, Long Island, c. 1933 (taken by SDW #400-6-4)
      • Lowrey, Mary R., outdoors, in front of blossoms with Phoebe R. Stanton, Locust Valley, Long Island, 1933 (taken by SDW #400-7-3)
      • Lowrey, Mary R., outdoors, holding flower from a bush, Locust Valley, Long Island, 1933 (taken by SDW #400-7-6)
      • Lowrey, Mary R., outdoors, blossoms behind, Locust Valley, Long Island, 1933 (taken by SDW #400-7-7)
      • Lowrey, Mary R., Faith A. Witter, Phoebe R. Stanton, Susan R. Witter, and unidentified boy, outdoors, next to a Christmas tree, Locust Valley, Long Island, 1934 (taken by SDW #400-12-12)
      • Lowrey, Mary R. (oversize headshot), c. 1934?
      • Lowrey, Mary R. (¾ length portrait), c. 1934?
      • Lowrey, Mary R., outdoors, holding a blossom, Locust Valley, Long Island, 1936 (taken by SDW #400-14-7)
      • Lowrey, Mary R., Phoebe R. Stanton, unidentified boy, and a dog, outdoors, Locust Valley, Long Island, 1936 (taken by SDW #400-14-8)
      • Lowrey, Mary R., Phoebe R. Stanton, and "Camilly," with horses, in Hamilton, Ohio (oversize), 1938
      • Lowrey, Mary R., holding a doll and wearing a Spanish headdress, 1938 (taken by SDW?)
      • Lowrey, Mary R., with a dog, 1938 (taken by SDW?)
      • Lowrey, Mary R., on a horse (2 views), 1938 (taken by SDW?)
      • Lowrey, Mary R., Phoebe R. Stanton, and a dog, Locust Valley, Long Island, 1939 (taken by SDW #400-17-4)
      • Lowrey, Mary R., Phoebe R. Stanton, Faith A. Witter, Susan R. Witter (on a rock with water in background), Locust Valley, Long Island, 1939 (taken by SDW #400-17-8)
      • Lowrey, Mary R.—"Christmas in Locust Valley, Long Island, (magic box)" [Eliza Gregory], 1940 (taken by SDW?)
      • Lowrey, Mary R., Mary C. Rentschler, Tinnie (Elizabeth Fishback), (8" x 10"), 1941
      • Lowrey, Mary R. (8" x 10"), n.d.
      • Lowrey, Mary R., wedding photograph, 1952
      • Lowrey, Mary R., and Charles F. Lowrey, wedding photograph, 1952
      • Morrison, Suzanne, wedding photograph, 1960s?
      • Rentschler, George A. Sr., ½ length portrait
      • Rentschler, George A. Sr., headshot
      • Rentschler, George A. Sr., ¾ length portrait
      • Rentschler, Gordon S., in front of train (Sequoia and Sagebrush), 1919
      • Rentschler, Gordon S., Mary Sweetser, Helen R. Waldon, Mary C. Rentschler, Phoebe R. Stanton, Mary R. Lowrey, Faith A. Witter, Charles Nagel? Locust Valley, Long Island, 1932 (taken by SDW #400-5-6)
      • Rentschler, Gordon S., Susan R. Witter, Mary R. Lowrey, Phoebe R. Stanton, Faith A. Witter, 1933
      • Rentschler, Gordon S., Clara Smith, Tommy Dorsey, John Smith, c. 1940s
      • Rentschler, Gordon S., Mary C. Rentschler, Mary R. Lowrey (Christmas in Locust Valley, L.I.), 1940
      • Rentschler, Gordon S., Mary C. Rentschler, home in Hamilton, Ohio, 1943
      • Rentschler, Mary C., ½ lenght portrait, c. 1920s
      • Rentschler, Mary C., Helen R. Waldon, Mary Sweetser, Locust Valley, Long Island, 1932 (taken by SDW #400-5-7)
      • Rentschler, Mary C., Phoebe R. Stanton, Mary R. Lowrey, Gordon S. Rentschler, 1939 (taken by SDW?)
      • Rentschler, Mary C., Phoebe R. Stanton, Mary Sweetser?, Julia C. Deane, and 2 dogs, Locust Valley, Long Island, 1939 (taken by SDW #400-17-5)
      • Rentschler, Mary C., Mary Sweetser?, Julia C. Deane, and dogs (walk in front of large body of water), Locust Valley, Long Island, 1939 (taken by SDW #400-17-7)